# MSc. Albi Dode



# **Summary**

Software Engineer/Developer, IT Support, Manual Tester, Technical Writer, and Data Protection Officer providing technical support, developing software programs, web sites, giving information security/DPO consultancy. I have knowledge in Agile methodology for leading teams in achieving excellence in client satisfaction, productivity, and profitability. Firm mindset with a drive to find solutions to new problems. Strong analytical skills and detailed to project's requirements. Adaption well in groups and a willingness to understand the various roles played by fellow team members. Perform tests and find ways to eliminate bugs in the programs. Build interactive and dynamic websites and experience with remote projects.

# Work experience

IT Support 2021

## astraia software gmbh

Support a wide range of technical and network solutions including Windows, MAC and monitoring of the systems. \* Gather and analyse information about the user's issue in order to determine the best way to resolve their problem. \* Point of contact for Windows Server issues troubleshooting and Database back ups & transferring (Sybase+PostgreSQL). \* Prepare and conduct technical and application trainings. \* Co-operate with our Sales and Product Management department. \* Make use of XML, Java, SQL skills for data analysis. \* Optimize IT Support workflow.

IT Support 2021 - 2021

### Leipzig International School

IT Service Desk - Solve ticket issues. Networking, Switches and Routing support.
 Data Backups. Update website and user manuals. Manage the wireless accounts. \*
 Support for Windows& Mac (Office 365 & Active Directory). \* Remote & In-place support (Software & Hardware). \*Provide ideas in meetings for new technical requirements and actual project scope.

Researcher 2019 - 2021

#### ESIT & University of Ulm

Development of a generic framework for mobile data sensing and mobile patient intervention for tinnitus patients. Data analysis and articles publications.

Collect, analyse and publish data related scientific articles. \* Support for monitoring, measuring and researching large amounts of data coming from TrackYourTinnitus smartphone application. \* Help in code troubleshooting and maintenance. \* Help bachelor and master students prepare their thesis preparation and writing. \* Development of new ideas related to the tinnitus topic through extensive data analysis and visualizations results from machine learning and algorithms implementation. \* Take part in scientific conferences. \* Co-author in different scientific articles with data analysis.

#### **Skills**

Languages & Databases

C++, C#, VB .Net, Java, Python, HTML/SQL/PHP, R, Sybase, PostfreSQL, MySQL

## **Applications**

Active Directory, GIT, Dita XML, Veeam, Baramundi, Ranorex, WireShark, Postman, CAS, Confluence, Zammad, Jira, LogicMonitor, WEKA, KNIME

# **Competencies**

- Handle multiple projects simultaneously
- Prioritisation skills
- Troubleshooting
- Analytical skills
- Network
- Coding
- Technical Support
- Quality Assurance
- Research in new technologies

# Languages

English, Italian, Spanish, Swedish, German

### Certification

GDPR - DPO

Startup Winner

#### BlueScreen

Develop back-end components, connect the application with other web services in PHP and SQL. \* White Box testing of the final version.

Technical Writer 2018 - 2019

#### Ericsson

Understood different user levels and writes to the appropriate level. \* Adhered to department and company standards, including templates and style guides. \* Wrote and explained code, operational procedures, APIs and manuals. \* Produced electronic documentation in addition to hard copy materials. \* Maintained a comprehensive library of technical terminology and documentation (via GIT checks). \* Analysed documents written in different tools and different projects to maintain continuity of the style of content. \* Managed updates and revisions to technical literature.

IT and DPO 2018 - 2018

# qPharmetra Sweden

\* Cisco Meraki for cloud management, VPN networking, and application control. \* Configure switches and Backups. IT support for Windows & Windows Server. \* Office 365 & Active Directory and SharePoint support. \* Use Veeam Backups. \* Remote & In place support. \* Point of contact for internal and external partners.

Lecturer 2015 - 2015

## Albanian University Tirana

Lecturer and for one semester in Tirana and Berat for the subjects: Computer Architecture & Web Applications.

IT support 2014 - 2015

### Albanian Psychologists Association

\* Made a website using in HTML/PHP/MySql and a documentation content management system using Java. \* Investigate faults in the network. \* Procure network equipment according to needs. \* Provide Windows & Windows Server support. \* Perform backups. \* Remote & In place support.

## **Technical Support Specialist**

2012 - 2014

#### Albanian Business Partner

\*Design and implement new network solution. \*Facilitated network support for hospitals in Tirana for a software written in Java. \* Windows support. \* Remote & In place support. \* Point of contact for internal and external partners.

Education

**Bachelor in Computer Science** 

2010 - 2014

State University of New York

Master of Science in Software Engineering

2015 - 2017

Mälardalen University

